# 哈喽 大家好
Hello, everybody.
# 今天买了两颗白菜
I bought two baicai (napa cabbage) today.
# 3块钱一斤 这里有五斤 15块钱
3 yuan per jin. Here's 5 jin for 15 yuan.
# 然后
and
# 我带了一锅汤下来
I brought down a pot of soup.
# 因为这个视频还没有开始剪辑
Because the video of this soup hasn't been edited yet.
# 所以我没跟我四伯爷说这个是什么
I haven't told my uncle what it is.
# 让他猜一下
Let him guess.
# 我先打开给你看一下是啥子
I'll open it up and show you what it is.
# 是不是那个卤水哦
Is that the master stock?
# 卤水
Master stock
# 不是的卤水
No, it's not.
# 特意带下来的 伯娘过来看一下嘛
I brought it down here on purpose. Auntie, come and have a look.
# 闻不出来这是啥子味道
I can't tell what it smells.
# 又不像魔芋
It's not like konjac jelly.
# 是不是很香
Doesn't it smell good?
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 很香是不
It smells good.
# 反正是放了油在里面的
It's got oil in it.
# 放了油啊
Oil?
# 这个正好就是一点油都没放
There's no oil in this soup.
# 点油都没得
Not even a drop of oil.
# 嗯 你看嘛
Well, you see?
# 这个像什么
What does this look like?
# 我给你说这个里面有些什么嘛
I'll tell you what's in this soup.
# 这个汤里面是放了2只鸡 2只鸭子
There are two chickens and two ducks in this soup.
# 然后2个肘子 一根大的火腿
Then two pork hocks and a large ham.
# 总共用了一二十斤的材料加水熬成的
It took a total of ten to twenty jin of ingredients to make this soup.
# 熬的啊
It's slow cooked.
# 还加了鸡胸肉 鸭胸肉
I also added chicken breast and duck breast.
# 用来扫底
To make the soup clear.
# 怪不得这么香哦 我都闻到香
That's why it smells so good. I can smell it.
# 这是开水四伯爷
This is called "Kaishui", uncle.
# 我说是有油脂的东西嘛
I thought there is something greasy.
# 闻到有点香反正
It smells good.
# 但是香的味道说不出来
The smell of aroma can't be described.
# 这个是开水
This is Kaishui.
# 这个加白菜叫开水白菜听说过没有 四伯爷
Have you heard of this dish "Kaishui Baicai", Uncle?
# 因为这个视频还没更
Because the new video hasn't been published.
# 所以这次我想在我四伯爷没看视频之前给他弄
So this time I want to get it to my uncle before he watches the video.
# 可以洗哈就是
I can wash it.
# 洗哈要得
Wash it.
# 太浪费了
Don't waste it.
# 三哒三块钱一斤
Three yuan per jin.
# 那不是咋子 三块钱一斤
You right. Three yuan per jin.
# 这个外面的青的拿给漆二娃炒酸辣的
The green ones outside are for Qi Erwa to stir-fry with chili and vinegar.
# 这个不能浪费了
This can't go to waste.
# 我之前还以为和卤水一样
I thought the soup was like a kind of master stock.
# 不是的卤水
No, it's not.
# 这个白菜好多哦
That's a lot of cabbage.
# 这个要（白菜）芯
This dish only needs the core.
# 啊 用这个中间黄的就可以了
Just use the middle yellow piece.
# 翻得转（锅）不 等会儿
Are you okay for tossing the wok?
# 没得问题的 怎么小看我哦
It's no problem. Don't underestimate me.
# 你说就说是小事一桩嘛
You should say it is a piece of cake.
# 先弄来煮
Blanch it first.
# 焯水 焯水了之后用汤来蒸
Blanch the cabbage... and then steam it in the soup.
# 蒸了之后再把这个汤烧开
Steam it and then bring this soup to a boil.
# 把这个白菜从汤里夹出来
Take this cabbage out of the soup.
# 重新把那个汤浇在上面
Pour that soup over it again.
# 好麻烦
So complicated.
# 麻烦你还没看到
You haven't seen the complicate part...
# 算了
Hmm...
# 你没看到更麻烦的 四伯爷
You haven't seen the complicate part, uncle.
# 其实我想跟你雕朵花的 我害怕等会被骂
Actually, I wanted to carve a flower from the cabbage. I was afraid I'd be scolded by uncle.
# 算了 没雕花
Forget it. It's not carved.
# 雕啥子花哦
What's with the flower?
# 就是这个白菜从中间划开 用剪刀剪一朵花出来
Cut the cabbage in the middle and cut out a flower with scissors.
# 剪朵花出来弄更好看
Cut out a flower to make it look better.
# 但是就是太浪费了等会要被骂
But it's a waste of food.
# 算了嘛 来漆二娃拿去
Forget it. Come Qi Erwa. Take it.
# 洗干净哦 洗来搣
Wash it.
# 嗯 好
Yeah, okay.
# 看 我们两棵白菜就这么一点
Look, this is all we have for two cabbages.
# 这个都我感觉
I feel...
# 多了点安
A little too much.
# 都还多了 其实芯只要一点都够了
That's more than enough. In fact, all you need is a little bit of core.
# 这个弄来洗 洗来弄
Let's wash this.
# 一哈拿去洗
Wash it.
# 一千多 我舀一勺多少钱哦
Over one thousand yuan... How much for one scoop?
# 这一勺啊
This scoop?
# 这一勺二十多
This is about 20 yuan.
# 一千多 害怕不止
If the whole thing is over a thousand. I think this is more than that.
# 不止这点 我们还有些
That's not all. We have more soup.
# 不止这点哦
That's not all.
# 一哈有二十多斤汤 这儿最多就是七八斤嘛
There is more than 20 jin of soup, but it's only 7 or 8 jin here.
# 洗干净了 洗干净了
It's clean now.
# 我就去整嘛
I'll do it.
# 要得啊
Yes.
# 要得 帮我端过来哈
Yeah, help me bring it over.
# 这个碗拿不拿过来
Do you need this bowl?
# 拿过来嘛 一哈
Yes.
# 汤弄来烧开
Bring the soup to a boil.
# 一哈就开了
It's quick.
# 还多麻烦
So complicated.
# 一般
It's okay.
# 好 要得了 看
Okay, come on, look.
# 这个汤浇在上面就要得了
Pour this soup on top and it's good.
# 金黄金黄的
Golden soup.
# 茶叶 像茶色
Tea color, like tea color.
# 这个叫开水
This is called "Kaishui".
# 开水淋在白菜上叫开水白菜
Pour the "Kaishui" on cabbage to make it "Kaishui Baicai".
# 有技术今天没炒糊
You got the skill, It's not burned today.
# 炒了点菜起来
Stir fried some dishes.
# 来吧
Come on.
# 来 四伯爷我先给你舀汤
Come, I'll serve you the soup first.
# 先喝汤喝这个里面的
Let's start with the soup and drink from this.
# 那个里面的喝了不够再加
If there's not enough in there we can add more.
# 你先喝来试哈 喝得惯不
You try it first. How do you like it?
# 有啥子喝不惯的哦
What's not to like about it?
# 我尝哈我的酸辣大白菜
I'll try my spicy sour cabbage.
# 可还是可以 就是水多了点的
It looks okay. It's just a bit too much water for stir fry.
# 这个汤的味道安逸哦
This soup tastes so nice.
# 是不
Yes.
# 诶 你今天还有个徒弟安
Hey, you have another apprentice right?
# 还有一个徒弟在宽菜那边帮忙 那边搞不赢
Another apprentice is helping out with Kuan Deli... they are so busy.
# 哦
Oh.
# 来 漆二娃自己舀
Qi Erwa, help yourself.
# 我说咋子之前都是两个徒弟 今天只有一个徒弟来
I know you got two apprentices, but today there's only one.
# 等到师弟回来我又去了
I'll go help when junior apprentice comes back.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 这个汤好喝安
This soup is good.
# 尝哈这个白菜嘛
Try this cabbage.
# 白菜才是主角
The cabbage is the star.
# 这个汤这么好喝你搞了一些啥子东西
This soup is so good, what have you done with it?
# 安
Hmm?
# 这原材料加起来可能有十多二十斤
The raw ingredients probably add up to 10 to 20 jin.
# 十多二十斤 有些啥子原材料嘛
10 to 20 jin? What kind of raw ingredients are there?
# 鸡 鸭 肘子 火腿
Chicken, duck, pork hock, ham.
# 哦呦
Oh!
# 之前给你说了你没记到
I told you before, but you didn't remember.
# 难怪不得这个汤这么好喝
No wonder this soup tastes so good.
# 没得记性的
Poor memory.
# 过几天我再弄一道炒饭给你吃
I'll make you some fried rice in a few days.
# 炒饭那个差不多要两三百块钱
That fried rice probably costs almost two or three hundred yuan.
# 两三百块钱一份安
Two or three hundred yuan?
# 啊
Ahh
# 要花些啥子材料哦
What kind of ingredients does it take?
# 还是有火腿有海参
There's still ham and sea cucumber.
# 还有虾
And shrimp.
# 还有其他的东西
And other things.
# 太多了 我一哈给你说不完 说了你也记不住
It's too much for me to tell you, and you wouldn't remember it if I did.
# 你整的东西好吃安
Your dish is delicious.
# 本钱太高了 我们农村哪里承受得住这么高的本钱嘛
But the cost is too high. How can we in the countryside afford such price?
# 不关事 反正是将就拍那个视频的
It's okay. It's for making best cooking video.
# 好嘛
Oh, yeah.
# 我给你舀饭了不
Do you want rice?
# 要得啊
Yes, I do.
# 少舀点 我多吃点这个白菜
Not too much. I'll have more of this cabbage.
# 这个白菜好好吃哦
This cabbage is so delicious.
# 你多喝点汤 四伯爷
Drink more soup, Uncle.
# 汤也好喝 白菜也好吃
The soup is good, the cabbage is good.
# 伯娘添饭不
Auntie, rice?
# 等会我自己舀
I'll do it myself later.
# 好了
All right.
# 本期视频就到这里
That's it for this video.
# 下一期
The coming video,
# 做扬州炒饭
I will make Yangzhou Fried Rice
# 这一次本来想雕个花的 我怕弄出来挨骂
I wanted to make a flower this time, but I don't want to be scolded for it.
# 所以没有弄
So I didn't.